Guide to the University of Chicago Board of Trustees Collection 1892-2000
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Board of Trustees. Collection
1892-2000
2 linear feet (4 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
This collection contains publications, correspondence, and ephemera documenting the activities of the University of Chicago Board of Trustees.
Information on Use
Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
The Board of Trustees, currently consisting of 55 members, governs the University of Chicago under provisions of the Articles of Incorporation, Bylaws, and Statutes. As well as providing financial support and fundraising leadership, the Board of Trustees oversees the University’s program goals, financial and physical resources.
The board is made of 9 standing committees: Audit, Executive, Financial Planning, Institutional Capacity, Investment, Medical Center Executive Committee, Outward Engagement, Trusteeship and Governance, and University Advancement.
Scope Note
The University of Chicago Board of Trustees collection is organized into 4 series:
Series I: Organization
Series II: Trustees and Committees
Series III: Events
Series IV: Fundraising
This collection contains brochures and booklets, with contents that range from Board policies and statements to event and program brochures, correspondence, certificates, letterheads, meeting notes, memorandums, press releases, newspaper and journal articles and clippings, various reports, directories, invitations, and fundraising brochures and proposals.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
University of Chicago. Board of Trustees. Minutes
University of Chicago. Board of Trustees. Correspondence of the Secretary. Records
University of Chicago. Board of Trustees. Presidential Search Committees. Records
Subject Headings
University of Chicago -- Administration; University of Chicago -- Board of Trustees
INVENTORY
- Series I: Organization
  This series contains brochures listing statutes and by-laws, miscellaneous booklets, certificates for trustees, correspondence, mailing labels, letterheads and envelops, meeting notes, memorandums, press releases, articles, and reports. The materials date from 1896 to 1996 and are arranged by type and then chronologically.
  - Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws, and Statutes, 1896-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brochures and Booklets, 1908-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from the Chairman of the Board, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mailing Labels and Letterheads, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Notes, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorandums and Correspondence, 1919-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases and Articles, 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1920-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Trustees and Committees
  This series contains directories of trustees and committee members, newspaper and journal clippings of trustees, and brochures listing members of the Board of Trustees. The materials date from 1929 to 1999 and are arranged by type and then chronologically.
  - A Trustees Who’s Who, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A Trustees Who’s Who cont’d, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees Directory, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees Directory, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees Directory, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Trustees Directory, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Trustees Directory, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Directory Brochures, 1942-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper and Journal Clippings, 1929-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series III: Events
  This series contains campus maps, menus and program brochures for events, invitations, and table assignment brochures. The materials date from 1892 to 2000 and are arranged by type and then chronologically.
  - Annual Dinner Brochures, 1921-1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Campus Map and Directions, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Event Menus, 1942-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Event Programs, 1955-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1892-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Invitations, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Table Assignments, 1949-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Fundraising
  This series contains proposals, reports, brochures, fundraising literature, and miscellaneous fundraising campaign materials. The materials date from 1936 to 1956 and are arranged by type and then chronologically.
  - Survey, Analysis and Plan of Fundraising, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Funding Campaign Reports and Brochures, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Responsibilities of Greatness, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Trustees Campaign Manual, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)